<contest-event id="8285">
  <event-date date="1870-6-25">June 25, 1870<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Halifax Contest</name>
  <contest id="1157">
    <name>Halifax Contest</name>
    <order>5</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id="340">Halifax Contest</group>
    <slug>halifax-contest</slug>
    
    <notes></notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  <contest-type-override id="12">Test Piece Contest</contest-type-override>
  <test-piece>
    <test-piece id="2184">&#39;Worthy is the Lamb&#39; and &quot;Amen&quot; from The Messiah</test-piece>
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="945">Piece Hall, Halifax, Yorkshire</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4287.htm

Band Contest - Piece Hall, Halifax
The second annual brass band musical contest in connection with the Halifax midsummer fair, took place in the spacious Piece Hall at that town, on which occasion there was a very large attendance, the receipts for admission amounting to upwards of £120. The following were the judges, Mr. S. E. Ricks, bandmaster 25th Regiment; Mr. Henry Whitaker, professor of music, Halifax; and Mr. George Raskoff, bandmaster 4th Dragoon Guards. It was arranged that each band should play &quot;Worthy is the Lamb&quot; chorus, and &quot;Amen&quot; chorus from Handel&#39;s Messiah, followed by a selection of their own. The first prize, £30 in money, was awarded to the Bacup band, and an alabaster timepiece, value £7 7s., to the bandmaster as his bona fide property, being subscribed for by the ladies of Halifax; the second prize, £18, was gained by Dewsbury Old band; third, £12, by Meltham Mills band; fourth, £8, by Leeds Model band; and fifth, £4, by Todmorden band. Then followed a solo cornet contest, by E and B flat cornets. The first prize, a silver watch and guard, value £6, was obtained by Chas. Auty, of Dewsbury Old band; the second, £1, by W. Greenwood, of Bacup band. The third and last was a solo-baritone and tenor contest, by E flat tenors and B flat baritones. In this contest, J. Lord, of Bacup band, won the first prize, a silver watch and guard, value £6; the second, £1, by R. Stead, of Meltham Mills band. The proceedings concluded at half-past eight in the evening, by all the bands unitedly playing &quot;Worthy is the Lamb&quot; Chorus, and &quot;Amen&quot; chorus, and the National Anthem.
8 bands competed.</notes>

  <created>Nov. 11, 2011, 3:40 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>April 3, 2016, 1:04 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="74179">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="6389">Bacup Old</band>
      <conductor id="305272">John Lord</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74180">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="2516">Dewsbury Old Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74181">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="135">Meltham and Meltham Mills Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74182">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="707">Yorkshire Evening Post Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74183">
      <result code="5">5</result>
      <band id="257">Todmorden Old Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="251986">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="1437">Irwell Springs</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
