<contest-event id="8276">
  <event-date date="1873-7-28">July 28, 1873<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Marske-by-the-Sea Contest</name>
  <contest id="1451">
    <name>Marske-by-the-Sea Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>marske-by-the-sea-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="944">Marske-by-the-Sea, North Yorkshire</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4287.htm

Band Contest - Marske-by-the-Sea
The seventh annual brass band contest took place at Marske when the weather was fine, and a large number of persons assembled in the field to hear the playing of the various bands named on the, programme. The contest took place in the same field as on previous occasions, and the lanes leading to it were pretty well thronged during the whole of the afternoon. The prizes offered for the band contest were: 1st, £20; 2nd, £14; 3rd, £8; which secured an entry of six brass bands, several of which have taken part in most of the contests that have taken place in the district. But of that number only three bands appeared to contest the prizes. A letter was received no later than yesterday morning, stating that in consequence of the illness of three or four of the members of the Leeds Model Band that band would not be present. A telegram was received stating that the Felling Chemical Works Band could not attend because of an accident - the falling of a chimney, we believe, and a telegram was also received from the Whitworth Colliery Band, stating that they could not be present owing to an accident in the colliery. But the disappointments did not end here. The judge appointed was Mr. J. T. Jones, bandmaster of the 5th Dragoon Guards, Dundalk, Ireland, but he was prevented by sickness from being present. He, however, on Sunday telegraphed to Mr. Brophy, bandmaster of the 101st Regiment, Salford, who attended as his deputy, and discharged the duties of judge in a manner that gave every satisfaction. The three contesting bands were as follows: Bramley Brass Band, 20 performers, leader, Mr. M. Hesling; conductor, Mr. J. Whiteley; grand selection, &quot;Maria Padilla&quot; (Donizetti); grand selection, &quot;Faust&quot; (Gounod). 4th Durham Artillery Band, West Hartlepool, 22 performers - leader, Mr. William Hogg; conductor, Mr. T. Hogg; grand selection, &quot;Reminiscences of Mozart&quot;; grand selection, &quot;I Capuletti&quot; (Bellini). Linthwaite Brass Band, 22 performers, conductor, Mr. E. Swift; grand selection, &quot;Meyerbeer&quot;; grand selection, &quot;Tannhauser&quot; (Wagner). In addition to the band contest, there was offered for competition an extra prize for the best solo on the cornet, a very pretty little cornet, made by F. Beeson and Co., of London, and worth £11 11s. After the bands had played over the first pieces, the cornet solo competition took place, ten names having been entered. Of those, seven put in an appearance, and played in the following order: 1. H. Milburn, jun., Middlesbrough; solo, &quot;Air Varie.&quot; 2. N. Sidney, Hartlepool; solo, &quot;Air Varie.&quot; 3. T. Hogg, Hartlepool; solo,&quot; Air Varie.&quot; 4. Mr. C. Auty, Linthwaite; solo, &quot; Air Varie.&quot; 5 Mr. E. Booth, South Bank; solo, 
&quot; How Vain to tell.&quot; 6. C. Carling, Middlesbrough; solo, &quot; Air Variations,&quot; 7. T. Lester, Middlesbrough; solo, &quot; Air Varie.&quot; The playing of the band was very good. Bramley rendered &quot;Faust&quot; very nicely, and was thought to stand a good chance. The general impression was that the first and second prizes lay between Bramley and Linthwaite. The Linthwaite possesses a first-class euphonium player, and the Bramley a very good baritone. At the close of the competition, which terminated about five o&#39;clock, Mr. Brophy ascended the stand, and delivered his decision. He gave the first prize to Linthwaite brass band, the second prize to the Bramley brass band, and the third prize to West Hartlepool band. In doing so, he stated that but for the variations of time in which the Bramley band played the first piece they might have obtained the first prize. He then said he would venture to say a word or two to the cornet players. He was afraid they attempted too much execution, and in doing so they either performed passages very badly or left out notes altogether. He thought it would be much better for them if they would take some simple melody, and by the feeling manner in which they played it prove their skill and artistic taste. He then awarded the prize to No. 3, Mr. T. Hogg, of. West Hartlepool, who, in response to numerous calls, gave a solo on the new instrument.</notes>

  <created>Nov. 11, 2011, 2:52 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Nov. 11, 2011, 2:58 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="74163">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="154">Linthwaite Silver Band</band>
      <conductor id="310006">Edwin Swift</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74164">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="2649">Bramley Temperance</band>
      <conductor id="311445">John Whiteley</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74165">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="18404">4th Durham Artillery</band>
      <conductor id="303245">Thomas Hogg</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74161">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="309">Felling Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74162">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="5204">Whitworth Colliery</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74160">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="707">Yorkshire Evening Post Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
