<contest-event id="7160">
  <event-date date="1864-8-27">Aug. 27, 1864<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Batley Contest</name>
  <contest id="1251">
    <name>Batley Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>batley-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="759">Batley, Yorkshire</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm

Band Contest - Batley
The exhibition of the Batley Floral and Horticultural Society was brought to a close by a brass band contest. The attendance of the public was exceedingly large. Five bands contested, and the judges (Dr. Spark, of Leeds, and Mr. James, band-master of the 8th Hussars) awarded the first prize to the Heckmondwike Albion, the second to the Dewsbury, the third to the Black Dyke Mills, and the fourth to the band attached to the works of Messrs. M. Oldroyd and Sons, Dewsbury. The decision appeared to dissatisfy a large majority of the people present, and a sort of indignation meeting was held on the ground, when a show of hands was taken on the position the bands ought to hold. The Black Dyke band was declared, by an overwhelming majority, to be entitled to the first prize, and the Heckmondwike Albion to the third. The conduct of the judges in leaving a tent in which they wore placed before the conclusion of the contest was severely commented upon by a member of the committee, amid much cheering. The proceedings, which threatened to become disorderly at one time, passed off pleasantly at the close, for the Birstal Rifle band having struck up some lively music, the good folks began to choose their partners, and whiled away the hours in dancing.</notes>

  <created>Aug. 28, 2011, 9:46 a.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Aug. 28, 2011, 9:50 a.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="63897">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="3487">Heckmondwike Albion</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63898">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="2511">Dewsbury Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63899">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="2">Black Dyke Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63900">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="5357">Messrs. M. Oldroyd &amp; Sons (Dewsbury)</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
