<contest-event id="7126">
  <event-date date="1863-8-17">Aug. 17, 1863<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Ancient Order of Foresters (Leeds) Contest</name>
  <contest id="1243">
    <name>Ancient Order of Foresters (Leeds) Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>ancient-order-of-foresters-leeds-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="745">Royal Park, Leeds</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm


The Order of Druids&#39; demonstration and brass band contest took place at the Royal Park, Leeds. The demonstration by the Druids was intended to be an imposing spectacle, but the rain which fell about noon interfered with the arrangements, and the interest became centred in a contest between the following brass bands: Dewsbury Borough, Deighton, Wike, Bramley 1st West V.A.C., Barnsley 37th W.Y.R.C., Dodsworth&#39;s Bradford, Baildon, and Kirkburton Temperance. The first prize was £12; second, £8; third, £5; and fourth, £3; and a beautiful aluminium gold cup, manufactured by Messrs. Wilkinson, of Birmingham, was presented to the master of the band that won the first prize. The judges were Mr. Thos. Martin, late bandmaster Royal Fusileers London; and Mr. Jackson, of Bradford. The same defect that was noticed so prominently in the contest at the Crystal Palace a short time ago was perceptible here - want of style in the solo playing, and in this particular the Yorkshire bands appear to be deteriorating. At the conclusion of the contest the prizes were awarded as follows: the 1st to Bramley, Mr. C. Auty taking the cup; 2nd to Dodsworth&#39;s Bradford ; 3rd to Baildon; and the 4th to Deighton. The following persona, selected from the above-named bands, competed for a valuable copper bronze cornet, mounted with German silver, and presented by Messrs. H. Distin and Co., London: - S. Bentley (Baildon), J. W. Dodsworth (Bradford), F. Auty (Dewsbury), A. Jackson (Deighton), T. Lawson(Bramley), and Edwd. Wray (Barnsley). The cornet was awarded to Edwd. Wray, he having manifested greater power of expression than his competitors, though Bentley and Lawson were superior to him in quality of tone. The other entertainments consisted of balloon ascents, an assault-at-arms, display of fireworks, &amp;tc., and the entire proceedings, which wore under the management of Mr. Enderby Jackson, of Hull, were of a satisfactory character. In consequence of the unpropitious state of the weather the attendance of spectators was not large.
</notes>

  <created>Aug. 27, 2011, 9:37 a.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Aug. 27, 2011, 9:46 a.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="63440">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="2649">Bramley Temperance</band>
      <conductor id="297270">Charles Auty</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63442">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="4016">Dodsworth&#39;s</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63443">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="4593">Baildon</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63438">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="3300">Deighton</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63441">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="6397">Barnsley Volunteers</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63437">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="3820">Dewsbury Borough</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63444">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5019">Kirkburton Temperance</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63439">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="3635">Wyke Old</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
