<contest-event id="7117">
  <event-date date="1863-7-25">July 25, 1863<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Alexandra Gardens (Leeds) Contest</name>
  <contest id="1239">
    <name>Alexandra Gardens (Leeds) Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>alexandra-gardens-leeds-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="741">Alexandra Gardens, Leeds</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm

A BRASS BAND CONTEST took place at the Alexandra Gardens, Leeds. The early part of the day was not very promising, and in consequence there was but a very meagre attendance. The gardens are admirably situated on the Roundhay road, and command an extensive view of the surrounding scenery. The contest commenced early in the afternoon, and was not concluded until dusk. The judges were Dr. Spark, Leeds, and Mr. Crow, band master of the 14th King&#39;s Hussars, stationed at Manchester. The judges were accommodated with a private tent, and the contest was carried on with the greatest fairness, Notwithstanding that the arrangements were such as to give satisfaction to fair competitors, we understand that not less than three bands offered bribes to Mr. Rayner, the manager, and we are glad to announce that the offers were indignantly rejected. The following bands contested: Batley Brass Band, conductor Mr. Benj. Hirst, leader Mr. John Brooke; Heckmondwike Albion, conductor Mr. John Brooke; Gawthorpe Britannia, leader Mr. John Briggs ; Farnley Iron Works&#39; Temperance Band, conductor Mr. John Emmett, leader Mr. Wm. Jasper; Leyburn Brass Band, band-master Mr. Robert de Lacy; Kirkstall Brass Band, conductor Mr. H. Jackson; Bradford (Dodsworth&#39;s), band-master J. W. Dodsworth; Dewsbury Borough Band, conductor Mr. Frank Auty, leader Mr. Charles Auty. The contest was carried on with much spirit, the various bands eliciting great applause, and there was considerable speculation as to the result. The first prize, £8, and a silver-plated euphonium, value twenty-two guineas, was awarded to the Heckmondwike band; 2nd prize, £6, and a silver-plated baritone, worth £19 19s, to Leyburn; 3rd, £4, and a challenge cornet, worth £12 12s., to Dodsworth&#39;s (Bradford); 4th, £2, and a flugal horn to the Dewsbury borough band ; and the 5th, £1, and a cornet to the Farnley Iron Works Temperance band. At the termination of the contest Smith&#39;s model brass band played terpsichorean music for the remainder of the evening, to the evident enjoyment of a large concourse of visitors. The euphonium forming part of the first prize is the gift of Mr. Besson, of 198, Euston road, London, and is a very handsome and rich toned instrument. In their report the judges referred to the Heckmondwike as an admirable band, and as having &quot;earned its laurels bravely&quot;. The bands gaining the second and third prizes were also referred to as being worthy of great commendation, &quot;the members exhibiting fine qualities as executants&quot;. The award seemed to give satisfaction to the contesting bands and to the audience, and everything passed off harmoniously.</notes>

  <created>Aug. 26, 2011, 11:15 a.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Aug. 26, 2011, 12:54 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="63387">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="3487">Heckmondwike Albion</band>
      <conductor id="298525">John Brook</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63390">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="585">Leyburn</band>
      <conductor id="312189">Robert de Lacy</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63392">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="4016">Dodsworth&#39;s</band>
      <conductor id="300457">J. W. Dodsworth</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63393">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="3820">Dewsbury Borough</band>
      <conductor id="297271">Frank Auty</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63389">
      <result code="5">5</result>
      <band id="3494">Farnley Ironworks</band>
      <conductor id="300914">John Emmett</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63386">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="1583">Batley Old</band>
      <conductor id="303164">Benjamin Hirst</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63388">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="8331">Gawthorpe Britannia Band</band>
      <conductor id="298443">John Briggs</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63391">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="3495">Kirkstall</band>
      <conductor id="303855">Henry Jackson</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
