<contest-event id="7185">
  <event-date date="1874-6-24">June 24, 1874<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Lofthouse in Cleveland Contest</name>
  <contest id="1256">
    <name>Lofthouse in Cleveland Contest</name>
    <order>10</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id="230">Lofthouse in Cleveland Contest</group>
    <slug>lofthouse-in-cleveland-contest</slug>
    
    <notes></notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="765">Loftus-in-Cleveland</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4287.htm

Band Contest - Lofthouse in Cleveland
This annual contest, which is now looked forward too in Cleveland with considerable interest, was held in a field belonging to Mr Robert Hudson, South Town, near Lofthouse. The present is the sixteenth annual contest, and notwithstanding it had some adverse circumstances to contend with, the recent strike and a severe thunderstorm in the district yesterday both operating against it, it met with an amount of success which does not compare unfavourably with previous years. There were six entries, viz., the Black Dyke Mills Band, conducted by Mr Samuel Longbottom; the Dewsbury Old Brass Band, conductor Mr Hartman; the Flockton Brass Band, conductor Mr John Brook; the Guisbrough First N.Y.V.A. Band; the Linthwaite Brass Band, conducted by Mr Edwin Swift; and the Wyke Temperance Band, conducted by Mr Brook. The music consisted chiefly of operatic selections, and the prizes, which amounted to £20, were eventually awarded as follows: Black Dyke Mills Band, first; Wyke Temperance second; and Flockton Brass Band, third. The winning band, it may be remembered, won the first prize at the brass band contest at Middlesbrough, on Monday, and has also been successful in various parts of the country. The judges were Messrs Jones and Fender, and their decision gave general satisfaction.</notes>

  <created>Aug. 29, 2011, 2:25 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Aug. 29, 2011, 2:49 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="64221">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="2">Black Dyke Band</band>
      <conductor id="305247">Samuel Longbottom</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64222">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="1440">Wyke</band>
      <conductor id="298525">John Brook</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64223">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="2683">Flockton United</band>
      <conductor id="298525">John Brook</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64224">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="2516">Dewsbury Old Band</band>
      <conductor id="302733">Mr. Hartman</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64225">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5391">Guisborough 1st N.Y.V.A.</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64226">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="154">Linthwaite Silver Band</band>
      <conductor id="310006">Edwin Swift</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
