<contest-event id="7188">
  <event-date date="1877-6-25">June 25, 1877<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Lofthouse in Cleveland Contest</name>
  <contest id="1256">
    <name>Lofthouse in Cleveland Contest</name>
    <order>10</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id="230">Lofthouse in Cleveland Contest</group>
    <slug>lofthouse-in-cleveland-contest</slug>
    
    <notes></notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  <contest-type-override id="9">Own Choice Test Piece Contest</contest-type-override>
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="765">Loftus-in-Cleveland</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4287.htm


Band Contest - Lofthouse in Cleveland
The annual Band contest at Loftus-in-Cleveland took place in a pleasantly situated field belonging to Mr Hunter on the south side of the town, in the presence of a large and gay company from all parts of the district. The prizes offered were £25 to the first, £15 to the second, £9, third, £6, fourth, and £3 fifth, and a prize of two guineas was also offered to the bandmaster bringing the most bands to the ground. There were eight entries, namely: Brotton Brass Band, Black Dyke Mills Band, Mirfield Band, Saltaire Band, Skelton Band, St. Helen&#39;s Band (Auckland), Linthwaite Band, and the Meltham Mills Band, but of these only the first six put in an appearance. The Brotton Band, under the leadership of Mr T. Woods, opened the programme with a fine selection from &quot;William Tell&quot;, and was followed by Black Dyke Mills, which gave in excellent style &quot;Homage to Wagner&quot;. The St. Helen&#39;s Band next gave in a creditable manner a selection from &quot;Tanhauser&quot;; and was followed by the Mirfield Band, which gave &quot;The Gem&quot; by Mozart; the Saltaire Band, which gave a selection from Meyeerbeer&#39;s &quot;Robert le Diable&quot;; and the Skelton Band, which gave one of the most interesting portions of Mozart&#39;s &quot;Il Flauto Magico&quot;. The second round, like the first, consisted of selections from the principal composers, and were &quot;Beliseno&quot; (Donizetti); &quot;Atilla&quot; (Verdi); chorus from Handel; &quot;Huguenots&quot; (Meyerbeer); &quot;Tanhauser&quot; (Wagner); &quot;Stiffelio&quot; (Verdi), and were given by the bands in the order named. The Saltaire Band fully sustained the excellent reputation it has gained during the past few years, and the two selections given by it were in themselves a rich musical treat. The Black Dyke Band, which has several times visited Loftus, and has on each occasion obtained a prize, also played exceedingly well, and between these two bands the chief prize rested, and was eventually given in favour of Saltaire. Mirfield was a good third, and St. Helen&#39;s a good fourth. Last year the first prize was won by the Linthwaite Band, Saltaire being second. and. Mirfield third. The prize to the bandmaster bringing the most bands was awarded to Mr T. Woods, who entered and led the St. Helen&#39;s and Skelton bands. .Mr Fender, of York, officiated as judge. The arrangements, which were under the superintendence .of Mr Wm. Walker, were, as usual, of the most satisfactory character.
</notes>

  <created>Aug. 29, 2011, 3:11 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Nov. 27, 2012, 11:12 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="64234">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="4899">Saltaire Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
      <test-piece id="1334">Robert il Diavolo [unknown arranger]</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64235">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="2">Black Dyke Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
      <test-piece id="2193">Homage to Wagner</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64236">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="4062">Mirfield Silver</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
      <test-piece id="523">Gems of Mozart [arr. T. Wright]</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64237">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="5103">St Helens (Bishop Auckland)</band>
      <conductor id="311966">Thomas Woods</conductor>
      <test-piece id="1102">Tannhäuser [unknown arranger]</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64238">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="6008">Brotton Old</band>
      <conductor id="311966">Thomas Woods</conductor>
      <test-piece id="1848">William Tell [unknown arranger]</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64239">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5098">Skelton United</band>
      <conductor id="311966">Thomas Woods</conductor>
      <test-piece id="967">Magic Flute [unknown arranger]</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64240">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="154">Linthwaite Silver Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64241">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="135">Meltham and Meltham Mills Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
