<contest-event id="7186">
  <event-date date="1875-6-24">June 24, 1875<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Lofthouse in Cleveland Contest</name>
  <contest id="1256">
    <name>Lofthouse in Cleveland Contest</name>
    <order>10</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id="230">Lofthouse in Cleveland Contest</group>
    <slug>lofthouse-in-cleveland-contest</slug>
    
    <notes></notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="765">Loftus-in-Cleveland</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4287.htm

Band Contest - Lofthouse in Cleveland
The seventeenth annual brass band contests at Loftus-in-Cleveland was held in a pleasantly situated field to the east of that place, and was attended with a greater amount of success than on any previous occasion, the weather being beautifully fine and the attendance large, and the programme of an interesting and popular character. No fewer than 4,000 persons were computed to be present, and the success of the gathering in this respect may he fairly attributed to the opening of the Saltburn and Loftus Railway this year, and the accommodation which was afforded on the occasion by the railway authorities. Hitherto, bands and visitors from a distance had to travel by road - a hilly and somewhat difficult one - from Saltburn, but this is now obviated by the new branch of the North-Eastern Railway, and a more delightful and picturesque ride it is difficult to find. The prizes offered, yesterday, amounted to about £50, £20 and a silver cup to the bandmaster being offered for the first, £12 for the second, £7 for the third, and £5 for the fourth. Six bands entered, viz., the Black Dyke, Felling Chemical Works, Mirfield, Northallerton Temperance, Skelton, and Wyke bands; but the Black Dyke and Wyke bands failed to put in an appearance. The other bands competing were: Felling Chemical Works Band (24 performers) Conductor, Mr T. Woods, leader, Mr Clemitson. Mirfield Brass Band (24 performers) Conductor, Mr John Brook. Northallerton Temperance Brass Band (15 performers) Leader, Mr Jenkinson. Skelton Brass Band (20 performers) Leader, Mr William Richardson. At the close of the competition the awards were as follows: Felling, first; Mirfield, second; Northallerton, third; and Skelton. The pieces by the first three bands were admirably rendered. The Skelton band is comparatively new, and not much was expected from it. There was afterwards a competition between four or five of the selected men from the competing bands, but the decision had not been made on our parcel being despatched. The arrangements, which were under the management of Mr W. Walker and a committee, were in every respect complete, and the romantic and beautiful situation of the ground fronting the ruins of the once noble fortress of Kilton was in itself no ordinary treat. Messrs J. A. Fender, of York, and John Wood officiated as judges.</notes>

  <created>Aug. 29, 2011, 2:54 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Aug. 29, 2011, 3:02 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="64227">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="309">Felling Band</band>
      <conductor id="311966">Thomas Woods</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64228">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="4062">Mirfield Silver</band>
      <conductor id="298525">John Brook</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64229">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="944">Northallerton Silver Band</band>
      <conductor id="304013">T. Jenkinson</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64230">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="5098">Skelton United</band>
      <conductor id="308162">William Richardson</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64231">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="2">Black Dyke Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64232">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="3635">Wyke Old</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
