<contest-event id="9995">
  <event-date date="1859-6-17">June 17, 1859<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Driffield Show</name>
  <contest id="1815">
    <name>Driffield Show</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="9">Own Choice Test Piece Contest</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>driffield-show</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="1322">Driffield, Yorkshire</venue>
  <notes>The &quot;tug of war&quot; was expected to be between the Driffield and Malton bands. The Driffield was freely backed against Malton, for there is now betting in band contests as well as in racing. It is notorious, however, that since the day when Tubal Cain first struck the first notes of music from his anvil, down to the Dritfield brass band contest, that whilst musicians are ambitious to produce the most harmonious chords from their instruments, they are ever the most inharmonious mortals amongst themselves. Of this there was another instance here. The Driffield band contains only twelve performers, whilst the Malton band has eighteen. The Driffield band grew alarmed at this superiority in numbers, and, as a counterbalance, insisted in retaining the assistance of Mr. Winn, the leader of Smith&#39;s Leeds Model band. The Malton men objected to this, and refused to play unless he were withdrawn. The Driffield band refused, and disputations and angry discussions ensued. It was at last decided that Mr. Winn should be allowed to play, and that the eligibility of the Driffield band in consequence of having his assistance should afterwards be decided by the judges and the committee. After the prize awards by the judges, the committee decided that the Driffield band was disqualified on account of having had the assistance of Mr. Winn, and gave the first prize to the Malton hand, and the second to the Brandesburton band. The Dritlield band being dissatisfied refused to take further part in the proceedings, and left the ground to play in the Market-place.</notes>

  <created>Feb. 4, 2012, 6:22 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>May 21, 2012, 8:49 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="84726">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="6618">Driffield Amateur</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
      <test-piece id="1359">Martha [unknown arranger]</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="84727">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="6451">Malton and Norton Sax Horn</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
      <test-piece id="1519">Atilla - cavatina [unknown arranger]</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="84728">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="6619">Brandesburton and Leven</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="84729">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="5250">Beverley Borough</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="84731">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="6620">Langtoft</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="84730">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="5249">Nafferton</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
