<contest-event id="6972">
  <event-date date="1863-6-29">June 29, 1863<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Liverpool Contest</name>
  <contest id="1190">
    <name>Birkenhead Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>liverpool-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="707">Zoological Gardens, Liverpool</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm

ZOOLOGICAL GARDENS - BRASS BAND CONTEST 
The brass band contest, which from the time of its announcement has awakened interest amongst musicians and the public generally, came off at the Zoological Gardens. Independently of the novelty of the fete, the fineness of the weather no doubt contributed materially to swell the attendance, the gardens being filled throughout the afternoon with a large number of visitors anxious to enjoy to the full the various amusements provided for them. The proceedings may almost be said to have commenced outside the grounds, the several bands having assembled according to previous arrangement in the open space adjoining St. George&#39;s Hall. No fewer than twenty-two were entered, a considerable being from this town and the immediate neighbourhood, whilst the others, and, as the result proved, many of them the best, came from the manufacturing districts - a fact proving the zest wherewith the operatives generally cultivate the art of music. 
Upon the formation of a procession they marched to the gardens, attracting en route considerable attention by their playing. On their arrival they separated into three portions-one being located in the space comprising the dancing platform, another taking up its position upon the bowling-green, and the third in the theatre. After performing for some time separately, they were brought together immediately in front of the orchestra, and the whole body of instrumentalists numbering about 400, played a selection of music under the leadership of Mr. Enderby Jackson, the band-contestt manager to the Crystal Palace Company, Sydenham. By this arrangement the judges were enabled to select the best bands, nine in number, composed of the 34th Staffordshire (Wednesbury), 29th West York R.V. (Dewsbury). 1st Albion (Heckmondwike), 25th Lancashire R.V. (Liverpool), 1st West York A.V. (BramIey), Wyke Operative Band (Yorkshire), Compstall Band (Cheshire), 4th Lancashire RV (Bacup) and 1st Tilsden R.V. These were then allowed in succession to perform the pieces they had previously chosen. Here the contest in reality commenced and it is but justice to say it was conducted with considerable spirit by the instrumentalists. Not only were the pieces well played so far as mere manipulation was concerned, but with an appreciation of the music which showed the players to be far more intimately acquainted with the classical compositions than might reasonably have been anticipated. At the conclusion of the band contest, the competition commenced for the cornet-a-piston soloists, the whole of whom, without exception, displayed a commendable proficiency in the art. The judges having arrived at their decision, the following prizes were awarded: First - £15 together with free gift of handsome three-pint cup, in aluminum gold, oxidised and burnished, from the manufactory of Messrs,.Wilkinson and Co., Birmingham - the Dewsbury Band. (This band performed upon instruments manufactured by Mr. F. Besson, of London. Second prize, £12 - the Albion Band, (Heckmondmike). Third prize, £8, the Compstall Band (Cheshire). Fourth prize - Band of the 34th Staffordshire R.V. (Wednesbury). A special prize of £6 (to the best band belonging to Liverpool and Birkenhead, provided it did not win one of the general prizes enumerated above) - band of the 25th Lancashire R. V., Liverpool, To the best cornet-a-piston player an electro-plated cornet, presented by Messrs. Distin and Co. of London - James Melling, bandmaster of the the Compstall Band. A richly-plated cornet-a-piston was also presented to the best cornet player by Mr Besson and Messrs. Hime and Son, the winner being Joshua Senior. The judges were Messrs Godfrey, B. M. Coldstream Guards; Thomas Martin, late B. M. 5th Fusiliers; .Alfred Crowe, B. M. 14th Hussars; Henry Synyer, 1st Battalion, Warwick, Birmingham; W. Wright, B. M. Yeomanry Cavalry, Knutsford. Referee, Mr. Enderby Jackson, who, with Mr. Goodfrey sen., awarded the prizes. A number of amusements of an attractive character constituted the remaining portion of the evening&#39;s programme.</notes>

  <created>Aug. 9, 2011, 1:44 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Aug. 9, 2011, 1:56 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="61627">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="3297">Dewsbury Rifle Corps</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61628">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="3487">Heckmondwike Albion</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61632">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="2792">Compstall Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61626">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="3489">Wednesbury Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61629">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5125">25th Lancashire Rifle Volunteers (Liverpool)</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61633">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="6389">Bacup Old</band>
      <conductor id="305272">John Lord</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61630">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="2649">Bramley Temperance</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61634">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="3754">Silsden Town Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61631">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="3635">Wyke Old</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
