<contest-event id="7261">
  <event-date date="1866-7-10">July 10, 1866<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Woodbridge Contest</name>
  <contest id="1270">
    <name>Woodbridge Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>woodbridge-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  <contest-type-override id="9">Own Choice Test Piece Contest</contest-type-override>
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="783">Woodbridge, Suffolk, England, UK</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm

Gala + Band Contest - Woodbridge
To the Editor of the Ipswich Journal - Sir, You published last week a letter from the conductor of the Sudbury Band, complaining of the managers of the recent Woodbridge Band Contest, the umpire, and the successful band. The former two parties are competent to defend themselves, if they care to do so; but on the part of the Bungay band I beg permission to assure your correspondent that we had no &quot;Circular Bass&quot; (whatever that may be), we knew nothing of the managers or the umpire, we assumed that they would conduct the proceedings with fairness and gentlemanly feeling, and we found no reason to doubt this, although our own very modest anticipations were more than realized, and the Sudbury band took only a fourth prize. 
I know little of the usages of such contests, but in this town we do a little cricket, and at that game it is, I believe, a rule that if exception be taken to an umpire, it must be before the play or not at all. Moreover, if a side has lost a match, and then quarrel with their opponents, disparage the umpire, and impeach his decisions, we are accustomed to think they really want a little training, not only in their play, but in their temper, taste, and manners. 
I am, Sir, obediently yours, 
Bungay, July 25th, 1866. Edgar Ray Childs 
. 
To the Editor of the Ipswich Journal - Sir Will you permit me to make a few observations relative to the Woodbridge Band Contest and the criticism that have appeared on it in your Journal. It is there stated &quot;the verdict passed in many cases did not accord with the award of the judges,&quot; When due allowance is made for prejudice and want of musical knowledge, it is not surprising that there should be some ground to differ from the opinion of the most competent of judges; that which does surprise and withal bears an amusing significance is that the critic is sparing of praise in proportion to the success of the respective bands. The band that took the first prize is represented as the black sheep of the whole, whilst those who failed, or took a low prize, are lauded with flattery. How is this? Is it to be attributed to the above mentioned prejudice, or is it the mistake of some amateur fiddler or pianist, or is it only an amiable attempt to soothe the Irritation of disappointment that the conquered might feel? If to the latter it has had a directly opposite effect, for it seems to have stirred up the bitterest black drop in Mr. Samuel Attfield. That gentleman seems to think himself aggrieved, and concludes his letter by remarking that the award of the discerning public was entirely in their favour. 
To every one this will be news, for beyond their personal friends no one ever expected the first prize to be taken by the Sudbury band, not even Mr. Attfield himself, as confessed by him previous to the contest. This band has become so inflated with its success at the Ipswich Contest, where there was only a couple of tenth-rate bands to beat, that they have formed opinions of themselves altogether absurd. Mr. Attfield&#39;s allusion to the difficulty of his selection is a fair proof of want of judgment, whilst his assertion that it is unusual to allow drums at a contest is incorrect. But why this jeremiad over drums. Does he after all regret the absence of his own? It may help to reconcile Mr. A. to the judge&#39;s award when be is informed that Mr. Smith was sent and highly recommended by Mr. Winterbottom. the bandmaster of the Royal Marines. 
As to the Woodbridge band playing harsh and discordant (Mr. A. says not a word of what the Journal did give it credit for, namely, having performed the second piece skilfully which atoned for the first), I have but one answer, it is, that if Mr. Attfield will find one &quot;man of good standing and reputation in the musical world,&quot; and allow me to find another (as judges), the Woodbridge band will meet the Sudbury at any time and for any amount they themselves shall think fit to name. The result of such contest I think I can foresee, and in imagination hear one of the Sudbury leaders exclaim to the other (for they have two leaders) 
&quot;Mine eyes smell onions; 
I shall weep anon. 
Good Tom-Drum 
Lend me a handkerchief.&quot; 
Should Mr. Attfield feel inclined to take up the gauntlet he can communicate his wishes at his earliest convenience to 
Your obedient servant, 
W. H. Stephenson 
July 26. 1866. Bandmaster 3rd S.R.V.</notes>

  <created>Sept. 22, 2011, 9:42 a.m.</created>
  <last-modified>June 3, 2012, 10:37 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="108063">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="8508">3rd Suffolk Volunteers (Woodbridge)</band>
      <conductor id="309742">W. H. Stephenson</conductor>
      <test-piece id="1912">Les Huguenots [unknown arranger]</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="108064">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="8509">4th Suffolk Rifle Volunteer (Bungay)</band>
      <conductor id="299284">E. R. Childs</conductor>
      <test-piece id="1975">Atala</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="108067">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="8511">14th Suffolk Rifle Volunteer (Beccles)</band>
      <conductor id="307733">M. Pringee</conductor>
      <test-piece id="1617">Anna Bolena [unknown arranger]</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="108066">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="5149">11th Suffolk Volunteer Rifles (Sudbury)</band>
      <conductor id="297203">S. Atfield</conductor>
      <test-piece id="1306">Fra Diavolo [unknown arranger]</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="108065">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="8510">6th Suffolk Rifle Volunteer (Stowmarket)</band>
      <conductor id="301959">H. Gooding</conductor>
      <test-piece id="1653">Gemma di Vergy [unknown arranger]</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="108068">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="8512">Ipswich Gas Company</band>
      <conductor id="307110">Walter Parker</conductor>
      <test-piece id="1693">Hallelujah Chorus [unknown arranger]</test-piece>
    </result>
    
    <result id="108062">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="8507">1st Suffolk Rifle Volunteer (Ipswich)</band>
      <conductor id="299883">W. Creasey</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
