<contest-event id="42832">
  <event-date date="2019-11-2">Nov. 2, 2019<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Gateway British Brass Band Festival (Open and Youth Section)</name>
  <contest id="6545">
    <name>Gateway British Brass Band Festival (Open and Youth Section)</name>
    <order>100</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id="614">Gateway British Brass Band Festival</group>
    <slug>gateway-british-brass-band-festival-open-6545</slug>
    
    <notes></notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="7213">Ritenour High School, St. Louis, Missouri, USA</venue>
  <notes>The Open Section is designed to cast a wide net to serve as many ensembles as possible.  Judging will be in the open.  Participating bands will be competitive or non-competitive (band’s choice) and there will be two subsections for competing bands: Youth and Adult.  Two noted educator/conductors will serve as judges/commentators.  Section awards will also be chosen.  Literature is Own Choice but must be a minimum of 16 minutes for those bands who have chosen to compete. Instrumentation is open to any brass instrument for the Youth subsection (high school or younger). Competing adult bands (high school graduates or older) must have traditional brass band instrumentation. Timing of the performance will be from downbeat to cut off of each piece performed.  A 30 minute stage time will be allotted each band.  Each band performing in the Open Section will receive a 40 minute clinic following their performance from rotating clinicians.  Each judge will record real time audio files.

Open/Educational Section                                                      Clinic
9:00 am           Ft. Zumwalt South Brass                                 9:30 – 10:10   
Short Break 
10:45 am         St. Louis Youth Brass Band                             11:00 – 11:40
 
11:40 am         Lunch Break
 
Championship Section
12:45 pm         Band A
1:30 pm           Band B
2:15 pm           Band C
3:00 pm           Band D
3:45 pm           Band E 
4:45 pm           Awards
6:00 pm           Dinner
 
Band Adjudicators
Dr. Sharon Huff
Dr. Kenneth Kroesche
Professor J.D. Shaw
Section Adjudicators
Dr. Jennifer Moder-Bell</notes>

  <created>Nov. 8, 2019, 11:45 a.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Nov. 8, 2019, 1:12 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="313595">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="18332">Fort Zumwalt South Brass</band>
      <conductor id="319760">Paul Ahlemeyer</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="313596">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="18333">St. Louis Youth Brass Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
