<contest-event id="7138">
  <event-date date="1864-6-24">June 24, 1864<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Buxton Contest</name>
  <contest id="1247">
    <name>Buxton Contest [1800s]</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>buxton-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="749">E.W. Wilmot&#39;s field, Buxton</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm


The anniversary of the establishment of free wells in Buxton by the Duke of Devonshire, was celebrated. Thursday morning broke with a cold drizzling rain, which continued throughout the day, with transient intervals of sunshine. From an early hour the railway companies poured in their thousands of excursionists who appeared to be ill-prepared for the inclement weather. The decorations were on a more extended scale than hitherto. Several fine arches graced the principal approaches to the town and the entrance to the Crescent, the latter by far the best, extending from the terrace walks to the roof of the hot baths. The inns and houses were also decorated, and the town generally wore a very gay and animated appearance. The Compstall Bridge and Buxton bands performed in various parts of the town, while the Morris dancers, composed of ten little girls dressed in white, with blue Garibaldi jackets and white straw hats, showed to great advantage. On Friday, the band contest took place, and the weather was more genial. The contest, which took place in a field belonging to the late Mr. E. W. Wilmot, at Burbage, commenced at one o&#39;clock, and was not decided until five. Each band played two pieces of its own selection. The following contested: Compstall Bridge (Temperance), Halifax (Rifle), Denton, High Lane, Chesterfield, Bakewell, and Matlock (Rifle). Nearly 3,000 persons were on the ground. The judges were Mr. Henry Nicholson, of Leicester; and Mr. J. C. Burck of the 49th Regiment, Manchester, who awarded the first prize to Chesterfield, while Bakewell and Matlock were to play off the &quot;tie&quot; for the second place. This decision was, however, withdrawn, the judges stating that they had made a mistake, and for Bakewell they substituted Compstall Bridge. The Secretary objected to this course, and the awards eventually stood as follows: Chesterfield, first, £12; Matlock, second, £8; Compstall Bridge, third, £3. The bands at the close gave a magnificent performance of the &quot;Hallelujah Chorus&quot; and &quot;God Save the Queen&quot;. On Saturday upwards of 800 children marched through the town in procession, headed by the Compstall Bridge Band, and were treated with plum cake, &amp;c., in the Crescent.</notes>

  <created>Aug. 27, 2011, 6:58 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Aug. 27, 2011, 7:02 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="63787">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="2509">Chesterfield Rifle Corps Band</band>
      <conductor id="310582">Thomas Tallis Trimnell</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63788">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="338">Matlock Band</band>
      <conductor id="304640">George Knowles</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63789">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="2792">Compstall Band</band>
      <conductor id="310699">Henry Tymm</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63793">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="488">Bakewell Silver Band</band>
      <conductor id="305616">Henry Marsden</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63791">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="1435">Denton Original</band>
      <conductor id="306453">E. Moss</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63790">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="12514">Halifax</band>
      <conductor id="300360">Isaac Dewhurst</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63792">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="2613">High Lane Silver Band</band>
      <conductor id="297088">Alfred Ardern</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
