<contest-event id="7201">
  <event-date date="1865-8-14">Aug. 14, 1865<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Kirkstall Contest</name>
  <contest id="1263">
    <name>Kirkstall Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>kirkstall-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="773">Kirkstall Abbey</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm


Band Contest - Kirkstall Abbey
Kirkstall feast - amongst the entertainments provided for the occasion was a brass band contest open to all amateur and volunteer brass bands in England (Kirkstall excepted). There were ten bands entered, and with the exception of the Farnley Iron Company and the Heckmondwike Albion bands, the rest of the bands entered appeared. Each band performed two pieces; and on the conclusion of the first trial the combined bands played the &quot;Hallelujah Chorus&quot; and after the second the &quot;Gladiator March&quot;. The bands who contested played in the following order, and the pieces selected for performance were chiefly operatic: - Bramley Artillery band, Armley brass band, Dodsworth&#39;s band (Bradford), West Hartlepool Operatic band, Oldroyd&#39;s (Dewsbury) band, Marriner&#39;s (Keighley) band, Black Dyke band, and Matlock Volunteer Rifle band. Before the awards were published a contest took place for a Jupiter cornet, value £9 9s, for which the following entered, one only allowed from each band: W. Rushworth, Black Dyke; J. Senior, Bramley; W. Ward, Dodsworth&#39;s; J. Naylor, Matlock; T. Hogg, West Hartlepool; C. Binns, Armley; D. Wilkinson, Dewsbury. It may be said that the playing of the bands was in every instance very good, but of course there were degrees of excellence, and the judges - who were Mr. G. Ruskoff bandmaster, 15th. Hussars; Mr. Thos. Martin, bandmaster, East York militia; and Mr. J. Deacon, bandmaster, 1st York militia - made their selections thus: In the band contest 1st prize (£28 16s), Matlock band; 2nd (£14 14s), Black Dyke; 3rd (£5), Marriner&#39;s; 4th (£2), was divided between Dodsworth&#39;s and West Hartlepool. For the cornet contest the prize was awarded to Mr. J. Naylor the leader of the Matlock band, the two first prizes thus going to the Matlock band. At the close of the musical contest balloon ascents and an exhibition of fireworks, and other amusements, concluded the proceedings.
</notes>

  <created>Sept. 5, 2011, 4:21 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Sept. 5, 2011, 4:26 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="64329">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="338">Matlock Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64328">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="2">Black Dyke Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64327">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="2455">Keighley Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64324">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="4016">Dodsworth&#39;s</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64325">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="1581">West Hartlepool Old</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64322">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="2649">Bramley Temperance</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64323">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="1636">Armley and Wortley Prize Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64326">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5357">Messrs. M. Oldroyd &amp; Sons (Dewsbury)</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64320">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="3494">Farnley Ironworks</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64321">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="3487">Heckmondwike Albion</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
