<contest-event id="7134">
  <event-date date="1866-9-1">Sept. 1, 1866<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Keighley Contest</name>
  <contest id="1244">
    <name>Keighley Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>keighley-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  <contest-type-override id="9">Own Choice Test Piece Contest</contest-type-override>
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="747">Keighley Agricultural Society Grounds, Skipton Road, Keighley</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm

KEIGHLEY DOG AND PONY SHOW AND BRASS BAND CONTEST. 
The second day&#39;s show of the Keighley Agricultural Society took place in the society&#39;s grounds, in Skipton road. The weather was again favourable, and the attendance was very good. The receipts at the gate wore upwards of £160, against £375 taken on Friday. The show of dogs was large, there being an increase over the number exhibited last year. The leaping of the ponies was quite a feature of the day, and gave much amusement. There were five entries in the brass band contest, and prizes were awarded to the whole of them in consequence of the Spinkwell and Calder Band obtaining the first prizes in each contest. The streets were on Friday illuminated, and were thronged with visitors to a late hour. 

Double Brass Band Contest - First contest, piece of own seclection; second, piece at sight. The Spinkwell and Calder Band obtained the first prize in both contests, but, according to rule, it had to give way in the second prize to the second-best; 2; Spring Head Band: 3, Bradford Model Band; 4, Kildwick Band; 5, Marriners&#39; Juvenile Band,</notes>

  <created>Aug. 27, 2011, 2:40 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Nov. 28, 2015, 10:52 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="63709">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="5330">Spinkwell and Calder Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63710">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="158">Haworth Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63711">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="3271">Bradford Victoria</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63712">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="5095">Kildwick and District Prize</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63713">
      <result code="5">5</result>
      <band id="5331">Marriner&#39;s Juvenile Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
