<contest-event id="7106">
  <event-date date="1862-8-6">Aug. 6, 1862<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Totnes Contest</name>
  <contest id="1235">
    <name>Totnes Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="11">Set Test and Own Choice</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>totnes-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="735">Totnes Castle</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm

The volunteer fete champetre took place in the grounds of Totnes Castle, for the benefit of the 17th D. R. V. The unfavourable weather, especially in the latter part of the day, to a very considerably extent marred the general success of the fete. The prizes offered for the brass band contest excited great interest. The prizes were - First £12, second, £5, third, £3; for which the bands of the 4th D.M.R.V. (Modbury), 17th D.R.V. (Totnes), 12th D.A.V. (Devonport Dockyard), and 1st D.R.V. (Dawlish), entered. A. prize of £2 was also offered for the best volunteer field bugler-eight competitors entered-Peter Watts, 4th D.M.R.V. (Modbury); George Bartlett, 17th D.R.V. (Totnes); Mr. McKeer, 2nd D.R.V. (Plymouth); James Donoghue, 1st D.R.V. (Exeter); John Tanner, 23rd D.R.V. (Clindleigh); F. H. Panter, 1st D.R.V. (Dawlish); Mr. Chapple, 9th D.R.V. (Ashburton); William Boobier, 14th D.R.V. (Tiverton). The regulation required each band to play in the contest two pieces, one of their own selection and the other a piece composed by Mr. Winterbottom for the occasion. The bugle prize was awarded to Mr. McKeer, of the Plymouth Corps; but Mr. Boobier, of Tiverton, was also &quot;honourably mentioned&quot; by the judge (Mr. Winterbottom). The first prize in the brass band contest was awarded to the Dockyard band; the second to the Modbury band; and the third to the Dawlish band. The recently-formed Totnes corps band, if they did not carry off a prize, monopolized the compliments of the spectators, who formed their opinions rather on the relative proficiency of the performers - that is, taking into consideration the opportunities the competitors had had for attaining skill in the use of their instruments - than by their approximation to sonic absolute standard of perfection. The attendance, notwithstanding the weather, was very good, and the pecuniary result satisfactory. A. £5 note was sent to the secretary, through the post office on the grounds, by an anonymous friend, towards the expenses of the fete.</notes>

  <created>Aug. 26, 2011, 9:30 a.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Aug. 26, 2011, 9:36 a.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="63346">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="5286">12th D.A.V. (Devonport Dockyard)</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63347">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="5136">4th Devon Rifle Volunteers (Modbury)</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63348">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="5145">Dawlish Rifle Corps</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63349">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="5287">17th Devon Rifle Volunteers (Totnes)</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
