<contest-event id="8297">
  <event-date date="1871-9-2">Sept. 2, 1871<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Queensbury Contest</name>
  <contest id="1326">
    <name>Queensbury Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="9">Own Choice Test Piece Contest</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>queensbury-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="953">Harrowins House Park, Queensbury</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4287.htm

Band Contest - Queensbury
The Black Dike Mills Band has rendered Queensbury famous in many parts of England as the centre of a district where some of the best amateur brass bands are to be found. This band carried off the first prize at the Crystal Palace against forty-four competitors; it has won numerous honours since, and still sustains its early reputation. A junior band has been formed at Messrs. Foster&#39;s works, and from this source youths of musical ability are drafted into the original Black Dike band, The firm keeps up both bands, finding teachers, instruments, and music books, With the view of further promoting a taste for music, the operatives of Queensbury, to the number of 104, agreed to subscribe £1 each as a guarantee fund to establish an annual brass band contest. 15s in the pound was paid up, and the committee offered prizes amounting in the aggregate to £55. The contest came off in a beautiful glade of the park adjoining Harrowine House, the residence of Mr. W. Foster, which had been kindly placed at the disposal of the committee, The weather was wet and threatening in the morning, but it brightened up as the day advanced, and the afternoon was calm, warm, and sunny. Queensbury put on its best face for the occasion. The roads were spanned with flags, and bunting was displayed from the church tower and from many houses, while across the road leading to the scene of the contest was stretched an inscription in blue and gold, announcing that the Queensbury Brass Band Contest was established in 1871. Thirteen bands had entered, and the following eleven put in an appearance: Buttershaw Mills, Mixonden, Bury Borough, Southowram Subscription, Meltham Mills, Linthwaite, Dewsbury Old Band, Royal Stainland, Batley (43rd W.Y.R.), Leeds Model, and Outlane. A stand was erected in the centre of the ground, on which the bands played. The judges were Mr. H Lindenberg (bandmaster 13th Hussars, Leeds), Mr. W. Allen (bandmaster 15th Regiment, Aldershot), and Mr. G. S. Calvert (bandmaster 2nd West York Yeomanry, Halifax). They were located in a tent adjacent to the players, which was carefully guarded, and waving over this was a white banner, inscribed &quot;Justice&quot;, in token that the performers would have fair play. The decision was left entirely to the judges, the committee not interfering with them in any way, a course which prevented any dispute. It was intended that each band should play two pieces, but as one selection round occupied nearly six hours, the performance of the second piece was waived. The judges stated publicly that the playing had been very good, some of the soloists being especially commended, The awards, received with applause, were as follows: 1, Meltham Mills, £25; 2, Bury Borough, £15; 3, Dewsbury Old Band, £10; 4, Outlane, £6; 5, Royal Stainland, £1. Upwards of 5,000 people were on the ground during the day, and mixing freely among the crowd were Mr. and Mrs. W. Foster and other ladies and gentlemen.

</notes>

  <created>Nov. 11, 2011, 4:35 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Jan. 6, 2020, 1:24 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="74220">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="135">Meltham and Meltham Mills Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74221">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="2497">Bury Borough</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74222">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="2516">Dewsbury Old Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74223">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="3715">Outlane Brass</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74224">
      <result code="5">5</result>
      <band id="5445">Stainland</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74229">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="1583">Batley Old</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74225">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="3498">Buttershaw Mills (Bradford)</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74228">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="154">Linthwaite Silver Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74226">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5793">Mixenden</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74227">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="4134">Southowram Subscription</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74230">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="707">Yorkshire Evening Post Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
