<contest-event id="8524">
  <event-date date="1873-8-30">Aug. 30, 1873<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Tow Law Contest</name>
  <contest id="1453">
    <name>Tow Law Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>tow-law-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="948">Tow Law</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4287.htm

Flower Show + Band Contest - Tow Law
The annual exhibition of the Tow Law Floral and Horticultural Society was held on Saturday, in a field pleasantly situated on the slope of the hill overlooking the ironworks, and commanding an extensive view of the valley of the Wear, with its rich and varied scenery. 
The handsome sum of £20 for a grand band contest brought together four bands, which each played two selections, the judge ultimately awarding the first prize of £8 to the Reeth band, conducted by Mr. Hunter, and led by Mr. J. Alderson, which played in an admirable manner a fantasia, &quot;Croix D&#39;Honneur&quot; by M. Belger, and the Hallelujah Chorus. The second prize, £6, Wooley band, conductor, G. Richardson, leader, C. Dunn, which performed selections from Verdi&#39;s &quot;Macbeth&quot; and Wallace&#39;s composition from &quot;Maritana&quot;; 3rd, £3, Shildon Saxhorn Band, conductor, F. Dinsdale, selections from Mozart&#39;s Twelfth Mass, and Donizetti&#39;s &quot;Lucrezia Borgia&quot;; 4th prize, £2, Crook band, conducted by Mr. W. Campbell, and led by W. Curry, whose selection was a fantasia from Reinholdt&#39;s &quot;Military Evening Camp&quot; and Metcalf&#39;s &quot;Queen&#39;s Minstrels&quot;. The Tow Law band, under the conductorship of Mr. J. M&#39;Intosh, and led by Mr. Wm. Campbell, played a grand selection of music on the ground, but was excluded from the competition, having previously won above the stipulated sum of money.</notes>

  <created>Dec. 8, 2011, 10:40 a.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Dec. 8, 2011, 11:01 a.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="75525">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="5300">Reeth Volunteer</band>
      <conductor id="303683">Mr Hunter</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="75526">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="6068">Wooley Colliery</band>
      <conductor id="308146">G. Richardson</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="75527">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="3601">New Shildon</band>
      <conductor id="300404">F. Dinsdale</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="75528">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="8499">Crook Saxhorn</band>
      <conductor id="298971">W. Campbell</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
