<contest-event id="8293">
  <event-date date="1873-6-3">June 3, 1873<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Darlington Contest</name>
  <contest id="1455">
    <name>Darlington Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>darlington-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="950">Greenbank, Darlington</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4287.htm

Gala + Band Contest - Greenbank, Darlington
At Greenbank there was a gala and band contest under the auspices of the Free Gardeners. The site of the contest was a small field some distance from the house, audit was soon full to overflowing - in fact so crowded was it that there was no room for aught but the bands to play. Only five of the six bands entered turned up - the Whitworth, the Hartlepool Volunteers&#39;, the Leeds Model, the Saltaire, and the Felling Brass Band. Mr. Jones, of York, acted as Judge. After playing once, the Judge required the three last named bands to play over; and when they had done so, to the astonishment of all he made the following award: Hartlepool first, Leeds Model second, and Saltaire third. During the afternoon there was little pleasure, owing to the crowded state of the field, the only amusement being that on the part of some rough boys and girls, who pelted each other with balls made of the long grass, and who broke up the only attempts made at kiss-in-the-ring or turzey. In the evening, however, the Albert Hill Brass Band played some good music, but the state of the ground precluded dancing.</notes>

  <created>Nov. 11, 2011, 4:16 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Nov. 11, 2011, 4:18 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="74200">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="5097">Hartlepool Artillery</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74201">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="707">Yorkshire Evening Post Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74202">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="4899">Saltaire Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74204">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="309">Felling Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="74203">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="4180">Whitworth &amp; Spennymoor Silver Prize Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
