<contest-event id="7202">
  <event-date date="1866-8-4">Aug. 4, 1866<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Kirkstall Contest</name>
  <contest id="1263">
    <name>Kirkstall Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>kirkstall-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="773">Kirkstall Abbey</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm

Gala + Band Contest - Kirkstall Abbey
A brass band contest came off in the Kirkstall Abbey grounds, when the following bands contested, namely: Spink Well Mills Band, Mr. H, Jackson, leader; Dewsbury Old Band, Mr. J. Peel, leader; Buttershaw Mills Band, Mr. W. Calvert, leader; Heckmondwike Albion Band, Mr. J. Brook, leader; and Dodsworth&#39;s Band, Mr. J. W. Dodsworth, leader. Each band played two pieces, after which the judges (Mons. J. Riviere, musical director, Adelphi Theatre, London, and Mr. A. Keonig, bandmaster, 13th Hussars, York,), awarded the prizes as follows: First, £14, Heckmondwike; second, £9, Dewsbury; third, £5, Spink Well Mills; fourth, £2, Dodsworth&#39;s. A solo cornet, value £5 5s, was next contested for by the leaders of the respective bands, and was gained by Mr. H. Jackson, Spink Well Mills.. The decisions of the judges gave every satisfaction to those taking part in the contest; as also to the visitors, of whom, however, there was not a very numerous attendance, the weather being very unfavourable for out-door recreation. The contest manager was Mr. J. H. Wright, of Kirkstall. Various entertainments - such as walking at pole over the river, climbing greasy poles, balloon ascents, &amp;c. were provided,</notes>

  <created>Sept. 5, 2011, 4:32 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Sept. 5, 2011, 4:35 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="64333">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="3487">Heckmondwike Albion</band>
      <conductor id="298525">John Brook</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64331">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="2516">Dewsbury Old Band</band>
      <conductor id="307325">John Peel</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64330">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="5330">Spinkwell and Calder Band</band>
      <conductor id="303855">Henry Jackson</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64334">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="4016">Dodsworth&#39;s</band>
      <conductor id="300457">J. W. Dodsworth</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="64332">
      <result code="5">5</result>
      <band id="3498">Buttershaw Mills (Bradford)</band>
      <conductor id="298946">William Calvert</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
