<contest-event id="7105">
  <event-date date="1862-7-14">July 14, 1862<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Penkridge Contest</name>
  <contest id="1234">
    <name>Penkridge Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="9">Own Choice Test Piece Contest</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>penkridge-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="734">Teddesley Park, Penkridge</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm

The Volunteer Fete, which took place at Teddesley Park, was an event to which not only the members of the Stafford and Cannock Rifle Corps, for whose especial benefit the fete was projected, but, many others in the county, have looked forward for some weeks past with very considerable interest, and we are glad to be able to say that it has been a decided success. 
The feature of the most general interest, perhaps, was the Volunteer Band contest, which attracted the attention of large concourses of persons. This contest was carried on at intervals throughout the afternoon, the prizes offered being £10 and £6. The bands which took part in the competition and the pieces they played were as follows: 

Cannock - &quot; Overture to the Caliph of Bagdad&quot; and &quot;Hallelujah Chorus&quot;; Langton - selections from the opera of &quot;Cinderella&quot; and &quot;The Stranger&quot;; Lichfield - selection from &quot;Attala&quot; and the overture to &quot;Fra Diavolo&quot;; Stafford Rifle - march, &quot;Retour&quot; (Kaestner) and &quot;L&#39;Orago Galop&quot; (Josef Gung&#39;l); Etruria Artillery - selection from &quot;Lucretia Borgia&quot; and the overture to the &quot;Caliph of Bagdad&quot;; Newcastle Rifle, &quot;Torquato Tasso&quot; (Donizetti) and the overture &quot;Les Fers aux Roses&quot; (Mari). Mr. F. Heidleman, bandmaster of the Royal Dragoons, was the judge. At the conclusion of the competition, Mr. Heidleman decided that the Longton band was entitled to the first prize; but the merits of the Lichfield and Etruria bands were so nicely balanced as to render another performance necessary to decide which was must deserving of the second prize. Accordingly, these bands played again, and then the judge awarded the second prize to the Etruria band. The decisions of the judge were received by the friends of the successful competitors with loud applause. </notes>

  <created>Aug. 26, 2011, 9:13 a.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Aug. 26, 2011, 9:23 a.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="63340">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="5284">Longton</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63341">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="5280">Lichfield</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63342">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="5905">1st Staffordshire Artillery</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63343">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5285">Cannock</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63345">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5283">Stafford Rifle</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63344">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5282">Newcastle Rifle</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
