<contest-event id="6976">
  <event-date date="1861-7-5">July 5, 1861<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Exeter Contest</name>
  <contest id="1191">
    <name>Exeter Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="12">Test Piece Contest</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>exeter-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="709">Northernhay Gardens, Exeter</venue>
  <notes>See 
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm 

The Volunteer Service Band Contest commenced on Thursday afternoon about five o&#39;clock. When we say the the performances were infinitely superior to what had been expected by those unacquainted with the general efficiency of the Rifle Corps Bands we are not paying a very high compliment perhaps to the performers. Little more than a musical clamour was expected. The affair, in fact, was an experiment. But the committee of the society must have been as agreeably surprised as other spectators generally to listen to the excellent style in which the pieces selected were given, and it several instances they were so well given as to elicit the warmest commendation from the judge (Mr. J, Smyth, the well-known conductor of the Royal Artillery Band). The following is a list of the bands engaged: 
Brass bands: 3rd D,A.V. (Teignmouth), established 1858; 6th D.A.V. (Dart mouth), established September, 1860; 1st D.R.V. (Exeter division), established January, 1860; 1st D.R.V. (Exmouth division), established January, 1860; 4th D.R.V. (Modbury) established June, 1860; 18th D.R.V. (Okehampton), established Sept., 1860; and 27th D.R.V. (Colyton), established January, 1801. 
Fife and Drum Bands: 1st D.A,V. (Woodbury) ; 2nd D.A.V. (Sidmouth); and 5th D.A.V. (Exeter) In addition to these the bands of the Brixham Artillery, and the Bideford, Tavistock, and Kingsbridge Rifles entered but did not appear. 
The contest was conducted by the several bands consecutively playing a piece of music of their own selection, and a piece written for them by Mr. Smyth, the order of playing being first determined by ballot. The prizes amounted to £80, viz.: For brass bands: 1st prize, £20, and a silver cup, value £5, for the bandmaster; 2nd, £13; 3rd, £10; 4th, £7. For the drum and fife bands ; 1st prize, £10, and a £3 cup for the band-master; 2nd, £7; and 3rd, £5. 

These prizes were awarded to the successful competitors on Friday afternoon, after a grand concert in the Castle-yard , which was attended by upwards of 8,000 persons, by the president of the society (Sir J. T. B. Duckworth, Bart, the High Sheriff of Devon.) The appearance of the hon. and gallant bart. on the platform in the uniform of a deputy lieutenant was hailed with loud and general applause. As soon as it had in some degree subsided Sir John explained the way in which it was intended to award the prizes, and called upon Mr. Smyth to state to which of the brass bands he awarded the first prize. 

Mr. SMITH : No. one band - (Loud cheers) 
Sir JOHN DUCKWORTH said the applause showed that the assemblage knew very well what was meant by the number; but for the information of those who might not he mentioned that the successful band was the Exeter and South Devon First Volunteer Rifles - (Renewed cheering.) - Now for the 
second, Mr. Smyth! 
Mr. SMYTH: Number seven - (Cheers.) 
Sir JOHN DUCKWORTH: Number seven is the band of the Exmouth company. (Loud applause.) Now, the next! 
Mr. SMYTH: Number three band has the third. (&quot;Hurrah!&quot; and cheers) 
Sir JOHN DUCKWORTH: The Sixth Devon Artillery Volunteers, Dartmouth - (Renewed cheers.) 
Mr. SMITH : Number six has the fourth. 
Sir JOHN DUCKWORTH: The Modbury band - (Loud applause) - Here you will allow me to remark that I believe in the conditions recently published with regard to the competition it was stated that the committee would not undertake to give four prizes unless there were as many as ten competitors, yet they are so much gratified with what has occurred today, and the high excellence of the competition that has been carried on, that I can announce on their behalf that although there are only seven competitors for these prizes, they are happy to give the whole of the four prizes which they have advertised. (Great cheering.) 
He added that he was desired to state that four small prizes, raised by private subscription, would he presented to the four best solo performers, to be selected by Mr. Smyth. 
Mr. SMYTH awarded the prizes as follows:-Number one, B flat cornet, of number one band (Exeter Rifles), Donoghue; number two, B flat cornet, number seven (Exmouth), Turner; number three, Jarvis, of the Dartmouth band; number four, John Cove, of the Modbury band. 
The prizes were then severally presented to the bandmasters by the High Sheriff, and at the conclusion of the ceremony Sir JOHN addressed the victors. The hon. Bart. said he could not allow the occasion to pass without remarking that it was not merely the ordinary kind of band contest, but was peculiarly marked by the fact that all the bands were those of volunteer corps. Nor could be see so large a number of persons assembled without remembering that they had been brought together not so much by the circumstance that there was a contest of bands, as that the members of those bands were for the most part taken from amongst their own relatives and friends, and wore, as he had said, volunteers. This was a most significant and important consideration, and the day was one of great importance to the volunteers of the county. Ho had read recently, in a speech made by one of the leaders of the movement in London - whether Lord Elcho or not he could not say - that a band for a battalion was a sine qua non. There could be no difference of opinion as to the importance of maintaining the volunteer movement, and be hoped they would think the Horticultural Society had not done ill in giving the bands an opportunity of showing what they could do. (Cheers.) In conclusion, Sir John urged on all the importance of supporting the volunteer movement, complimented the several bands on their performances, remarking that they bad perfectly astonished him, and chewed that whether a volunteer was a member of a band, a rifleman, an artilleryman, or anything else, he undertook his duties con amore. (Enthusiastic applause.) 
Mr. Smyth was then called forward, and greeted with enthusiastic cheers. 
The two Exeter bands, accompanied by a number of members of their respective corps, and with the two silver cups carried aloft, then paraded the principal streets of the city, and everywhere received an ovation, 
It should be added that the silver prize cups were supplied 
by the Messrs. Ellis, of Exeter.</notes>

  <created>Aug. 10, 2011, 12:51 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Aug. 10, 2011, 1:42 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="61652">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="5134">1st Devon Rifle Volunteers (Exeter division)</band>
      <conductor id="309604">M. Spratt</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61653">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="5135">1st Devon Rifle Volunteers (Exmouth division)</band>
      <conductor id="302445">R. W. R. Hallett</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61651">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="5133">6th Devon A.V. (Dartmouth)</band>
      <conductor id="303957">Stephen Jarvis</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61654">
      <result code="4">4</result>
      <band id="5136">4th Devon Rifle Volunteers (Modbury)</band>
      <conductor id="299801">John Cove</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61655">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5137">18th Devon Rifle Volunteers (Okehampton)</band>
      <conductor id="299651">James Coombe</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61656">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5138">27th Devon Rifle Volunteers (Colyton)</band>
      <conductor id="309478">William Smith</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61650">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5132">3rd Devon A.V. (Teignmouth)</band>
      <conductor id="310614">T. Tucker</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61658">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="5140">Bideford Rifles</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61657">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="5139">Brixham Artillery</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61660">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="5142">Kingsbridge Rifles</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61659">
      <result code="W">Withdrawn</result>
      <band id="5141">Tavistock Rifles</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
