<contest-event id="39453">
  <event-date date="2020-7-11">July 11, 2020<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>New Zealand National Championships (A Grade)</name>
  <contest id="216">
    <name>New Zealand National Championships (A Grade)</name>
    <order>10</order>
    <contest-type id="18">Sacred, March, Set Test and Own Choice Contest</contest-type>
    <group id="43">New Zealand National Championships</group>
    <slug>new-zealand-national-championships-a-grade</slug>
    
    <notes></notes>
    <region id="18">New Zealand</region>
    <section id="12">A Grade</section>
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    <test-piece id="101">Of Men and Mountains</test-piece>
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="2313">Christchurch, Canterbury, New Zealand</venue>
  <no-contest>140th Edition (Brett Baker Chief Adjudicator)


&gt;&gt;&gt; CONTESTS CANCELLED DUE TO CORONA VIRUS PANDEMIC

Statement of the BBANZ management committee:

Given the ongoing uncertainty about what will happen when the current lock-down period ends, the likelihood of continuing significant restrictions on travel and gatherings, and the financial impact these restrictions are already having on your players; the BBANZ management committee has made the difficult decision not to hold the 2020 National Contest.  This decision was not made lightly as we wanted the contest to proceed if possible and knowing there is some support for the major event in our calendar to go ahead. However, the safety and well-being of our members are paramount, and we believe this is the right call.
We also believe that it is important to our movement that a Christchurch contest is well attended. This wouldn&#39;t be the case this year given the number of bands who have already told us they wouldn&#39;t be able to attend. For that reason, we have decided that the 2021 contest will be held in Christchurch from 14 to 18 July, with the Wellington contest moved to 13 to 17 July 2022 and the Dunedin contest moved to July 2023.</no-contest>

  <created>April 4, 2018, 5:56 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>April 15, 2020, 9:39 a.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
