<contest-event id="6971">
  <event-date date="1861-7-1">July 1, 1861<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>Liverpool Contest</name>
  <contest id="1190">
    <name>Birkenhead Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>liverpool-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="707">Zoological Gardens, Liverpool</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4286.htm


VOLUNTEER BAND CONTEST - Yesterday afternoon a band contest took place in the Zooloplcal Gardems in connection with a gala held there for the benefit of the Liverpool United Friendly Tontine Societies. Unfortunately the weather was most unfavourable, rain heavily throughout the afternoon and evening; the attendance consequently, was but limited compared with what it would have been had the day been fine, 
The competition was restricted to the bands of the various rifle and artillery corps of Liverpool. It had been anticipated that the prizes would bring out a large body of competitors; indeed, it was publicly announced that 300 performers would be present. The number in attendance yesterday, however, fell far short of 300, only seven bands entering the lists for the prizes offered - a handsome silver cup of the value of ten guineas, furnished from the establishment of Mr. Meyer, Lord street, and £3 in money for the second best band. The motive which prompted the societies in question to offer these prizes will be at once apparent, and therefore little need be said about that. They had in view no doubt the double purpose of obtaining an addition to their funds by the speculation and furnishing an extra treat to the members and friends who were expected to assemble in large numbers on the occasion. But it may last be mentioned here that it is a matter of regret that contests of this description are not got up oftener, and that prizes on a more liberal scale and also more numerous have not been presented at other hands. Some of our volunteer bands are composed entirely of young musicians, many of whom were altogether ignorant of the art until they joined the service, and these contests would form a powerful incentive to them in gaining that knowledge of their instruments and of the science in general which is so necessary to make them really efficient performers. 

The competition was delayed for some time yesterday, in consequence of one or two little disputes respecting some of the Intending competitors being eligible and the unpropitious state of the weather, and the proceedings were not commenced until nearly five o&#39;clock. The judges appointed were Mr. Wright, of Knutsford, Cheshire (bandmaster of the Earl of Chester&#39;s Yeomanry Cavalry), and Mr. Squire Greenwood and Mr. G. A. Phillips, of Liverpool. The Order in which the bands played, and the compositions they performed, were as follows: 

17th L.A.V. 13 performers. Mr. W. H. Longden bandmaster who was also the leader. - Quick March, &quot;Heck Von Daobdstein&quot; and &quot;La Chateau Morceaux Polka&quot;. The majority of this band are very young men, and their playing did not betoken a long acquaintance with &quot;the art divine.&quot; The first piece they performed was the march, in the commencement of which there was every indifferent attempt at an effective crescendo. The instruments generally were out of tune, the tenors and basses especially, and the leading cornet was near half a tone flat in some passages. The hand wore not happy in their selection either, &quot;Hook Von Daobstein&quot; being a poor rendition. They were not much more successful in &quot;La Chateau Morceaux Polka,&quot; though it was played in better time and tune than the first-framed piece.
11th L.R.V. 13 performers. Bandmaster and leader,_ Mr. Henry, Moore. Quickstep from the opera of Traviata and a quickstep including well known airs sung by the Christy&#39;s Minstrels. This band is composed of mere boys, who have only been in the service about eleven months, and as none of them had any knowledge of music when they joined, great allowance must be made in their case. In the Christy&#39;s .Minstrels quickstep they were not nicely together, and the baritones were sadly out of tone in some parts. But the quickstep of selections from &quot;Traviata&quot; was a most decided improvement upon their first essay, being well in tune and correct as to time; Indeed, looking at the character of the music - not by any means of a simple style - it was rather astonishing to find comparative novices in music displaying such an appreciation of so classic a composer. The manner in which they acquitted themselves in the second section of their performance did them and their instructor infinite credit. We shall not be far wrong In saying that, if they exercise diligence and perseverance, they will seem be enabled to take a most respectable position as instrumentalists. 
1st comp of 1st battalion L.B.V., 19 performers. Mr. J. B. Cooper ; leader, Mr. J Broadhurst.- - Slow march, &quot;Pearl of Italy&#39;,&quot; by M. Marie, bandmaster of the national guard of Paris, and a selection from the first act of the opera of &#39;Lucrezia Borgia,&quot; arranged by Mr. Broadhurst. This was doubtless the best band upon the ground, whether as regards its general construction or its ability and really musician-like taste of its members. Their first piece, commencing with a very beautiful adagio, replete with fine harmony and modulation, and succeeded by an effective encore movement, was admirably rendered, light and shade being imparted to the various passages with a skill and judgment that certainly were not equalled by any other band taking part in the contest. Their secon piecte, the selection from &quot;Lucrezia Borgia,&quot; was also exceedingly good, and marked by the good taste and discernment which distingnIehed their first effort. Mr. Broadhurat&#39;s cornet solos. and Mr. Platt&#39;s E flat clarionet playing were greatly admired, and the same remark applies to the other soloists. Indeed, the entire performance of this excellent band, unmistakeably showing, as it did, the ability of the bandmaster, was listened to with evident satisfaction by the assembly. 
9th L.A.V. - Twelve performers. Mr. Joseph Monkhouse, bandmaster; Mr. William Swinnerton, leader. Selection from the opera of &quot;Maritana&quot; and duetto from the opera of &quot;Trovatore&quot;. The better piece was given first. It is a very nice movement, and tolerably well arranged. Mr. Swinnerton played a pretty cornet solo, but the accompaniments were anything but in tune, the tenors especially being quite wide of the mark. The andante movement, however, was got through fairly upon the whole, but there was a slight hitch in passing to the presto passage. This part was somewhat marred by crescendo upon the chord of the seventh which could have had a good effect had it been nicely done - being given dreadfully flat. The concluding portion of the piece, however, was capitally played. Whatever were the defects in the first, they were amply atoned for in the second section of their display. The selection from &quot;Maritana&quot; did them credit. It was played well throughout, and there was a nearer approach to something like a correct interpretation of the ideas of the author. The unison passages particularly were brilliant and spirited. We cannot say much for the arrangement of the selection, though, and should imagine that it did not come from any master hand. Some of the most beautiful passages are spoiled by he disjointed, abrupt, medley-like manner in which hey are strung together, irrespective of scientific connection. It is but just to the band to state that :hey laboured under some disadvantage in consquence of the contra-bass man not being in attendance. 
51st L.R.V. 16 perfomers. Leader, Mr. James Twist &quot;Number Three Quadrille,&quot; St. Claude, and a slow march, author&#39;s name not known. The quadrille was the first piece played, but it was not a very happy effort, the want of time and tune being quite apparent. The test piece was a slight Improvement upon the former, and the instruments were better together. Allowance must also be made for the performers, as they are principally very young men. They should study the cultivation of the ear, and pay greater attention to the effect of piano and forte than they appear to have done. 
12th L.A.V.2 performers. Mr. J. D. Richardson, bandmaster and leader. Quick step, &quot;The Persia,&quot; by Mr. George Fish, of Manchester and &quot;The Reigning Beauty Waltzes&quot; by D&#39;Albert. The playing of this band in the quick step was not everything that could be desired, the basses and tenors being open to the same unfavourable comment as in some of the former instances - too flat. One or two passages in the piece were nicely given. The waltzes were rendered in a pleasing manner. 
25th L.R.V. 15 performers. Mr Joseph Dattler bandmaster and leader. Selections from &quot;Preclosa&quot; and the well known &quot;Charleston Quadrille,&quot;- The exhibition of skill and taste made by this band&#39; wad certainly of anything but a high order, and they cannot consistently be complimented upon the pleasure they afforded those with &quot;ears musical&quot; amongst the company. The instruments generally were fearfully out of tune, the worst being the E flat clarionet of the leader, which was not far off half a tone flat. We must also take exception to the arrangement of the music they played, which is neither marked by taste nor judgement. The construction of the band, too, is anything but first-rate. Perhaps the members are like some of the other performers alluded to, have only recently gained a knowledge of the elementary principles of music. It is to he hoped that. this is the case as there will be the greater chance of their improving. 
The playing of the band of the 25th completed the programme of the musical portion of the day&#39;s amusement,. and after a short deliberation the judges called upon the bands of the 1st battalion L.R.V. and that of the 9th L.A.V. to play again. The former played a nice selection &quot;La Favorite,&quot; and the latter a selection from &quot;Trovatore.&quot; Both were exceedingly well rendered. After another consultation by the judges, it was announced by Mr. Simpson, the manager of the gardens, that they had awarded the 1st prize to the band of the 9th L.A.V,. and the second to the band of the 1st battalion L.R.V. 
Mr. J. B. Cooper had, before the contest commenced, lodged a protest against Barrow, of Ditton, of the band of the 9th L,A.V., being permitted to play with them, on the ground that he lived in another county, and more then 15 miles from Liverpool, the conditions of the contest being that all the competitors should be bona fide members of volunteer bands belonging to Liverpool. In reference to this protest,. Mr Simpson said there had been some disphte on the point, but in had been shown that Barrow was on the books of the captain of the corps, and the judges had decided that it did not matter where he lived, he was entitled to play in the contest. </notes>

  <created>Aug. 9, 2011, 1:26 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>June 29, 2015, 9:23 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="61622">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="5122">9th Liverpool Artillery Volunteers</band>
      <conductor id="306241">Joseph Monkhouse</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61621">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="5121">1st Liverpool Rifle Volunteers (1st Company)</band>
      <conductor id="299677">J. B. Cooper</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61619">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5119">17th Lancashire Artillery Volunteers</band>
      <conductor id="305251">W. H. Longden</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61620">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5120">11th Lancashire Rifle Volunteers (Preston)</band>
      <conductor id="306282">Henry Moore</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61623">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5123">51st Lancashire Rifle Volunteers (Liverpool)</band>
      <conductor id="310692">James Twist</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61624">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5124">12th Liverpool Artillery Volunteers</band>
      <conductor id="315404">Thomas D. Richardson</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="61625">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5125">25th Lancashire Rifle Volunteers (Liverpool)</band>
      <conductor id="300105">Joseph Dattler</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
