<contest-event id="7151">
  <event-date date="1875-7-5">July 5, 1875<event-date>
  <event-date-resolution>D</event-date-resolution>
  <name>West Hartlepool Contest</name>
  <contest id="1131">
    <name>West Hartlepool Contest</name>
    <order>0</order>
    <contest-type id="13">Other</contest-type>
    <group id=""></group>
    <slug>west-hartlepool-contest</slug>
    
    <notes>None</notes>
    
    
  </contest>
  
  <test-piece>
    
  </test-piece>

  <venue id="754">The Old Cricket Field, West Hartlepool</venue>
  <notes>See
http://www.ibew.org.uk/misc4287.htm

Band Contest - West Hartlepool
Decidedly, the most attractive and the most successful brass band contest ever held in West Hartlepool came off in the old cricket field. Mr Thomas Hogg, the talented conductor of the Durham Artillery 
Volunteers, was the principal promoter, and the character of the arrangements made testified to his great judgement. The locale was adjacent to the town and, besides being easily accessible; was as far removed as possible from the distracting noises so common to railway-encircled towns. It was also magnificent holiday weather; most of the places of business were closed, and thousands visited the field where the contest was held, the grand stand being filled by a highly respectable company. The prizes, four in number, amounted to £52. 
There were originally ten entries. Eight of the bands so entered put in an appearance, those eight being among the very best in the north, and Mr Hogg deserves the highest credit for collecting so many good bands. In the unavoidable absence of Mr. Smith, of Hull, Mr Broady, of Manchester, assisted by Mr J. C. Shepherd jun.,of West Hartlepool, officiated as judges. The following bands competed: Coxhoe Temperance Brass Band, Wyke Temperance Brass Band, Middlesbrough Brass Band, Whitworth Brass Band; Felling Brass Band, Saltaire Brass Band, Wyke Old Brass Band;;Northallerton Temperance Bras Band. The awards fell as follow: 1st prize, £25, Saltaire; 2nd prize, £14, Felling; 3rd prize, £8, Whitworth; and 4th prize £5, Wyke Temperance Brass Band. This decision, apparently, afforded unqualified.satisfaction. An extra prize was offered, for the. best solo on the cornet, consisting of a splendid desideratum cornet, value ten guineas; from the eminent firm of Besson and Co., instrument makers, Euston Road, London. The cornet solo competitors played in the following order: J. Hunter, Richmond; T. Jenkinson, Northallerton; J. Raine, Spennymoor; J. Allen, Middlesbrough; J. Paley, Saltaire; H. Jackson, Wyke Temperance. Jackson and Paley tied; and, after playing over again, the judge awarded the prize to Jackson.</notes>

  <created>Aug. 27, 2011, 8:29 p.m.</created>
  <last-modified>Aug. 27, 2011, 8:36 p.m.</last-modified>

  <results>
    
    <result id="63831">
      <result code="1">1</result>
      <band id="4899">Saltaire Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63830">
      <result code="2">2</result>
      <band id="309">Felling Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63829">
      <result code="3">3</result>
      <band id="4180">Whitworth &amp; Spennymoor Silver Prize Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63826">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="5351">Coxhoe Temperance Brass Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63828">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="1619">Middlesbrough (Milburn&#39;s)</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63833">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="944">Northallerton Silver Band</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63827">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="1440">Wyke</band>
      <conductor id="303855">Henry Jackson</conductor>
    </result>
    
    <result id="63832">
      <result code="">Unknown Result</result>
      <band id="3635">Wyke Old</band>
      <conductor id="310730">Unknown</conductor>
    </result>
    
  </results>
</contest-event>
